so New Gods - made
meditation and you said in the past and
I'll just read what you say
Metta meditation is thus amounting of
your mind from the lighting in all
giving into the possibility of acting
from in in that way let me kindness is
experienced correctly indirectly not
yours yeah what I meant was you don't want to
yeah what I meant was you don't want to
be doing or fabricating kindness
artificially I mean you can do that as a
as a form of management as we spoke
before your mind is great variable but
that's not the loving-kindness
meditation because if that's done
rightly that's on the level of journals
and he can certainly result in the mind
development to the level of becoming
another man brahma vihara see they're
done properly so it's not just your
casual beaming gradient happy thoughts
it's really seeing the basis of your
real will experiencing complete
equanimity towards the basis of failure
well when I say basis I mean that there
is that a will is bound with its
inseparable from it's determined by if
you're indifferent towards the
determination of their will you cannot
possibly be experiencing the real world
and then also you have no choice but to
be free from your will towards people
and the basis of your will its others
not just again you might have ill will
by the time they will manifest it's
usually aimed at somebody but the basis
of it is just the factual presence of
others in the general sense others
different than me different than this
point of view so if you start
experiencing a calamity on that level
and there is no your will that can
develop further down the line
so in practical terms you just have to
see that no matter how justified your
real will might be towards somebody a
person that he'll will and that notion
of personality isn't separated
inseparable from the physical aspect of
their body their body of my body of our
bodies and their physical aspect is
subjected to basically to sickness aging
death it's it's truly not in your
control so then you realize that even
any wheel that has intentionally been
inflicted upon it from others it was
done circumstantially so because they
themselves are not fundamentally the
owners of their body in this means they
do own it as a mistake as a petitioner
so appropriate things around it but once
you realize the you can own nobody can
own their burrows everybody is subject
to the same universal principles of
Anita and things not being in control so
then things that you do experience on
account of intentions of others you
can't take in that ultimate sense they
will then produce your real will in
return you would see it basically a
circumstantial like beings acting out of
ignorance and I don't mean that in a
patronizing sense like forgive them
they're ignorant
just factual like you know that when
there is ill-will and you it's because
you've taken your body to be permanent
to be to be in control and now you're
expressing the you will or last for that
matter so when you see it in others you
see the same thing so by understanding
it in yourself you'll understand it in
others and then it just it becomes
impossible for your will to arises for
as long as you don't ignore that fact
that they are not in control their own
five aggregates the way they present
themselves because if they were they
will be like truly mass they wouldn't be
subject to any impermanence and sickness
and death nothing but they are so
they're not so when they act like
they're gonna last forever you just see
clearly that's out of the same delusion
that you would be acting
if you're making the same same mistake
so that's where if you were to
understand that you basically understand
the whole nature of a ninja if you were
to genuinely practice Metta meditation
like like impossibility of ill-will and
then yeah you you want automatically
what you're gonna feel towards them is
compassion not a sort of smarmy tree
hugging sort of type of compassion just
to all of the Radian beings just
indulging basically self indulging but
more of a genuine compassion of oh yeah
there's a genuine ignorance there and if
they would only know better they
wouldn't have not done there and you
know they're perfect because nobody
actually wants to be acting out of
ignorance unless they're already great
what about well if the oil is present
you just first step is you must not act
out of it why bother with my speech then
eventually you should stop acting I
don't like even in your mind in terms of
having the unwholesome thoughts that's
just something that's a new like a
rising of those things possibility of
acting by body possibly taken by speech
even possibility of act in my mind
they're not on you those things present
themselves as possibility of the present
there is an experience of real will but
you are the one intentionally delighting
in it entertaining it and then
proliferating it further so that's so
new and that's what you don't want to do
when you stop doing that then you'll be
perfectly capable of enduring there a
reason your world so you will no mind
affected by your will as mind affected
by your will but that's that's all it
would be so you can order this by saying
it in that manner you already start
recognizing that you can't own it even
if you want you and then if when you're
fully cannot when you fully sort of
discern that then there won't be any
will any more it will it's one basically
a disagreeable experience in regard to
others is appropriate in his mind it's
an automatic
that's what the Buddha said sometimes he
instructs people detail he spends lots
of time instruction it but then they go
into the opposite despite all the
efforts that he put in into into
teaching that said but because of that
his mind the target is mine doesn't
experience any ill-will or an also
thought he experienced a disagree all
here he experienced disagreeable feeling
seems like oh look at his foolish man
I've been wasting my time so he doesn't
regard everything is pleasant but he
said that disagreeable feeling cannot
persist and overwhelmed the mind of the
target are and basically turn it into it
will aimed at that person
and what about thinking about you know
kind of thoughts before anything cool
you know what you don't have a will but
you well if you're thinking about kind
thoughts you're most likely going to be
thinking on the level of other people as
other selves which means you're just
revolving around the problem of taking
things as mine which means sooner or
later you will will replace that
kindness so your fabrication and
management I mean it's only relatively
effective in a sense of just kind of
pushing it away for a bit longer and so
on so yes you need to recognize that you
should not be dwelling in entertaining
your will and sort of giving rise to it
when you can and certainly acting out of
it but thinking that you can just
replace it with thoughts of kindness
just focus on this experience as opposed
to that experience that's only does it
replaces one experience with the other
experience but doesn't bring the
understanding of the nature of
experience all in itself it cannot bring
that because you're just concerned with
the content of that experience and just
replacing one with the other but if you
don't know that you're supposed to see
beyond the content of the experience
into the nature of experience the
universal principles which is what
Dharma is then you never you will never
look there because because you need to
you need to be told and then recognize
that and then some anything I could've
seen it won't be shown by itself
you can't stumble upon them or
accidentally so think kind thoughts it's
still better thinking kind thoughts is
still better than thinking unwholesome
thoughts but don't mistake that as a way
of out of both wholesome and unwholesome
thoughts which is what you want to
achieve because that's what matter does
matter is basically absence of ill-will
doesn't mean a lot because that's just
completely different experience absence
of love as well that's why if you do
brahma vihara correctly the highest of
them is the anonymity to pay complete
indifference in paternoville